(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
（ラプラスの生誕祭は）割とレベルの高い合格点を超える
(La+ birthday lives) always exceed my expectations,
生誕祭をオールウェイズ出してくれる
delivering a high level of quality every single time.
どこから来たんですか？
Where did you come from?
スト6の方から
From the Street Fighter 6 community.
開会してるんでしょ？
The event is opening, right?
閉会しています！
It's closed!
開会してるんでしょ？
It's opening, right?
閉会しています！
It's closed!
さっき開会してるって言ったじゃん
You just said it was opening!
閉会しています！
It's closed!
ラプラス・ダークネスの生誕祭は…
The La+ Darknesss birthday live is...
閉会しています！
Closed!
みんな！吾輩の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとね！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to my birthday live!
まずは1曲目、夜行性ハイズ！
First up, the first song: Yakousei Haizu!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
凝り固まった 忘れてたい
Stiffened up, I want to forget it all
そんな顔でいつまで戦うの？
How long will you fight with a face like that?
また一人で
Alone again
愛しても、愛しても
Even if I love you, even if I love you
そのたびに不意に不安が顔を出す
Every time, anxiety suddenly shows its face
巻き戻るように
As if rewinding
どうして力尽くまで、さらに百まで
Why must you go until exhausted, even to a hundred?
飲み込む悲しみだけは
Only this sadness that I swallow down
なくなってくれないの
Refuses to disappear
そうして逃げ場もないのに
And so, with nowhere to run
マイナス百から始まる動機の
Embracing the days of motivation
日々を抱き舞う
That start from minus a hundred
夜行性ハイズ
Yagousei Haze (Nocturnal Haze)
ちょっと泣いて
A little cry,
無理もしたら
and if I push too hard,
ここへおいでよって言ったって
even if I say, "come over here,"
これからを分かち合おうか
shall we share what's to come?
眠たいが眠れないまだ境界
Sleepy but I can't sleep, still at the boundary.
僕ら何処に向かって歩み合っていたんだよ
Where were we walking toward each other?
消せない最低は密度かな
Maybe the density is the unerasable low.
なんか吐き出せれば丁度いい奴でいたいのか
Do you want to be someone who's just right if they can spit it out?
知りたい消えたいも異常じゃない
Wanting to know, wanting to disappear, it's not abnormal.
よしよしのできすぎにほら吐き出しちゃおう
There, let's spit it out in the midst of too much comforting.
君は泣いたって綺麗だよ
You're beautiful even when you cry.
さらば愛に止まって前を向いて笑って行こうじゃない
Farewell, stay in love, let's look forward and go with a smile.
寂しくない 悲しくない
I'm not lonely, I'm not sad.
塗り重ねた強がり深い青洗い流せたら
If I could wash away the deep blue of layered bluffs...
バイバイをバイバイを バカみたいな世界にありがとう
Bye-bye, bye-bye, thank you to this foolish world.
探さないでね
Don't look for me.
そして僕らは広くも狭くも熱くも寒くもないこの部屋で
And so we, in this room that's neither wide nor narrow, hot nor cold,
抱き合って息するの
embrace and breathe.
常識外れを外れて二人だけの合言葉で鍵をかけたら
Going beyond the unconventional, if we lock up with our secret word,
さあどんな夜を過ごそうか
now, what kind of night shall we spend?
だけど痛い だから痛い
But it hurts, that's why it hurts.
優しさが染み込んでいく
Kindness is soaking in.
唱和を始めようか
Shall we start the chant?
眠たいが眠れないまだ境界
Sleepy but I can't sleep, still at the boundary.
声を何度だって送り合って保ってきましたが
We've kept it up by sending our voices back and forth, but...
辞めよう 逃げよう 大丈夫だよ
Let's stop, let's run away, it's okay.
もう寝たっていいのちゃんと僕が守ってあげるから
It's fine to sleep now, because I'll properly protect you.
おはようをしよ また今日にしよ
Let's say good morning, let's make it today again.
よしよしのできすぎにほら吐き出しちゃおう
There, let's spit it out in the midst of too much comforting.
僕も泣いちゃってやばいから
Because I'm crying too, it's bad.
さらば愛に止まって前を向いて笑って行こうじゃない
Farewell, stay in love, let's look forward and go with a smile.
弱虫な僕たちは
We cowards...
変わっても変わってない
haven't changed even if we have.
終わらない今日も吐いて光ってく 光ってく
Spitting out today that doesn't end, and shining, shining.
辛いのは暗いけど二人で乗り越えるさ
Being in pain is dark, but the two of us will overcome it.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えとね、まだまだ続くから
Um, it's still going on, so...
めちゃくちゃ楽しんでってね！
please enjoy it to the fullest!
バイバイ、バイバイ、バイバイ、バイバーイ！
Bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye!
東京・渋谷 20時すぎ
Tokyo, Shibuya, past 20:00
今回、ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど
I heard there's a birthday celebration for Laplus-san this time...
え、マジですか！？
Eh, are you serious!?
あの、え、ラプラスさんってあのホロライブの！？
Um, eh, Laplus-san from Hololive!?
僕、あのー、アレ、待ち受けにしてるんですよ
I, uh, have her as my wallpaper.
しかも今回のアレが「ラプラス・バースデイ2025」らしくて
And apparently, this event is "Laplus Birthday 2025"...
えー、マジでショックです
Eh, I'm seriously shocked.
でも幸せならOKです！
But if she's happy, then it's OK!
ね、あたしのことが好きなら気づいて
Hey, if you love me, then realize it.
気づいて 気づいて 気づいて
Realize it, realize it, realize it.
夢を見せて落として分かってくれないの
Won't you show me a dream, drop me, and understand me?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you.
二度と触れないで
Never touch me again.
パラサイト / 作詞・作曲 DECO*27
Parasite / Lyrics & Music: DECO*27
ちょっと待ってどこからおかしくなったの
Wait a second, where did it start going wrong?
駄目なところも好きになれてよかったのに
I wish I could have come to love even your bad parts.
パッと飲んで誰かに埋めてもらえたら
If I could just have a quick drink and have someone fill the void,
あなたのこと忘れられると思っていた
I thought I'd be able to forget about you.
肝心なとこ相性良くないけど繋がってるなら悪くはない
Our compatibility isn't great where it counts, but if we're connected, it's not bad.
騙し騙し生きていっちゃって
Just keep living while deceiving yourself.
優しくされると余計に辛いけど冷たくされるの望んでないよ
It's harder when you're kind, but I don't want you to be cold either.
あたしだけでいいって信じちゃって
Believing that I'm enough for you.
馬鹿だ
I'm a fool.
ね、あたしのことが好きなら気づいて
Hey, if you love me, then realize it.
気づいて 気づいて 気づいて
Realize it, realize it, realize it.
夢を見せて落として分かってくれないの
Won't you show me a dream, drop me, and understand me?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you.
二度と触れないで
Never touch me again.
全勝 1 2 の 3 で 流れ星
Total victory, on the count of 1, 2, 3, a shooting star,
パラサイト
Parasite
#ラプラス・バースデイ2025
#LaplusBirthday2025
ねえ、私のことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me,
気づいて、気づいて、気づいて、気づいて
please notice, please notice, please notice, please notice
夢を見させてよ
let me dream.
どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？
What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong?
ねえ、私のことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me,
手も繋いでよ
then hold my hand too.
どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？
What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong?
手も離さないで
Don't let go of my hand.
パラサイト、パラサイト、パラサイト、パラサイト
Parasite, parasite, parasite, parasite
あー、もう、私のことが好きなら
Ah, geez, if you love me,
気づいて、気づいて、気づいて、気づいて
please notice, please notice, please notice, please notice
夢を見させてよ
let me dream.
どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？　どしたの？
What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong?
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの？
Do you like me now that I've become yours alone?
ずっと ずっと 騙してきたんだね
You've been deceiving me for so, so long, haven't you?
アンドロイドガール
Android Girl
想いは何だっけ？
What were my feelings again?
錆びついた腕で何度僕を求めた？
How many times did you reach for me with those rusted arms?
ずっと
Always...
何千回愛を再起動して
How many thousands of times will you reboot love?
ちょっとだって変われやしないや
It won't change even a little bit.
何千回愛を再起動して
How many thousands of times will you reboot love?
ちょっとだって変われやしないや
It won't change even a little bit!
ホロライブでラプラスさんの影が薄いというお話なんですが
There's a story that your presence in Hololive is quite weak...
いや、納得できないね
No, I can't accept that.
Q. ラプラスさんの魅力は？
Q. What is your charm?
ないんだな、それが
Actually, there isn't any!
どうもこんにちは 君の分身です
Hello there, I'm your alter ego.
何の冗談か 眼を擦ってみる
Thinking it's some kind of joke, I rub my eyes.
影が二つ伸びて
Two shadows stretch out...
そしてまた幕は上がる
...and the curtain rises once again.
もう一人自分がいたらなんて あなたは言いました
"If only there was another me," you once said.
そんな真摯な願いが 僕を呼んだのさ
That sincere wish of yours is what called me here.
そりゃ願ったとも
Of course I wished for it!
悲しく全ての英才(エイジェイ)
Miserably, all the gifted ones...
暇は無いから 拙速 殺生 意味など無いなら退場
No time to waste, quick kill, if there's no meaning, then leave!
ねえ こんな事より大事な事があるんだよ いいだろ？
Hey, there's something more important than this, okay?
ええ やります やります 何でもやります 僕はお前の分身です
Yes, I'll do it, I'll do it, I'll do anything, I'm your alter ego.
終末(スリーマライ)で 冥想(メサイア)は You?
In the end, is the Messiah you?
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you? Who are you?
嗚呼 混濁を指して 僕は誰？
Ah, pointing to the confusion, who am I?
ねえ 有りもしないけど 独り 醒めぬ夢
Hey, it's not real, but it's a dream I can't wake from.
奪い去ってしまえよ さよなら
Just take it all away... Farewell.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は 誰は君？
Dear Doppelganger, who is you? Who is you?
蝕まれた存在に きっと気付かないね
You probably won't notice your eroded existence.
鳴り止まない 冷め止まない 奇跡の輪廻が狂った
The never-ending, never-cooling cycle of miracles has gone mad.
世界を染め上げろ パッパッパ
Dye the world, pa-pa-pa!
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Something seems off this Monday.
一つ 二つと 崩れゆく辻褄が
One by one, the consistency crumbles...
僕を再送(サイキ)する
...and retransmits me.
「お前は一体誰だ」と
Asking, "Who on earth are you?"
ちょっと待って 知らない火の粉も知らない言葉
Wait a minute, sparks I don't know, words I don't know...
そりゃいつの間にやら 影は解けていく
Before I knew it, the shadow was dissolving.
僕はなんだろう
What am I?
ねえ どこか存在を返して
Hey, give me back my existence somewhere!
相対様々 決定 肯定 恍惚を 毒を頂戴
Relative various, decide, affirm, ecstasy, give me poison!
もう居場所はここに無い事分かってるんでしょう
You know there's no place for you here anymore, right?
ねえ 奪われたんなら 奪い返せばいいだろう
Hey, if it was stolen, just steal it back!
今度は僕の番だ
Now it's my turn.
終末(スリーマライ)で 侵略(インベーダー)は You?
In the end, is the Invader you?
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you? Who are you?
嗚呼 混濁を指して 僕は誰？
Ah, pointing to the confusion, who am I?
待て それは僕の手だ 命の椅子は一つだけ
Wait, that's my hand! There's only one seat for life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は 誰は君？
Dear Doppelganger, who is you? Who is you?
転げ落ちた一粒 今日は焼き果てる前に
One grain that rolled off, today before it burns out...
誰でもいい 何でもいい 器をください
Anyone is fine, anything is fine, give me a vessel!
狂った世界が染め上げた パッパッパ
The mad world has dyed it, pa-pa-pa!
それはずっと続く人の煩悩さ
That's the ever-continuing human worldly desire.
乱れ合って 慈しみ合っても されど
Mixing together, loving each other, and yet...
欠けたピース 昔の天気予報 また 愛を
A missing piece, an old weather forecast, love again...
騙し合って 生まれ変わる いにしえを
Deceiving each other, reborn from ancient times...
僕の方が ちゃんと君を生きてやるから
Because I'll live your life better than you...
君も次の誰か ちゃんと座らなくちゃ
You must also seat the next person properly.
もう分かってんだろう 何をすればいいかさ
You already know what you have to do.
どうか 誰か僕に 奇跡をくれ
Please, someone give me a miracle!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you? Who are you?
嗚呼 混濁を指して 僕は誰？
Ah, pointing to the confusion, who am I?
もう止まらない 戻れない どうもこんにちは 君の
Can't stop, can't go back... Hello there, I am your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that's me, that's me!
蝕まれた存在に 世界が気付こうがもう
Even if the world notices the eroded existence...
鳴り止まない 冷め止まない 奇跡の輪廻が狂った
The never-ending, never-cooling cycle of miracles has gone mad.
世界を染め上げるさ 上手くやりやがる
I'll dye the world! You're doing a good job.
パッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelganger
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello there, I am your doppelganger.
わー！
Waa!
紗痲 / 作詞・作曲：煮ル果実
Shama / Lyrics & Composition: Nil Fruits
邪な もっと執心はファムファタール
Wicked, more obsessed with the femme fatale
嘘も削ぎ落とし ジュースを煽るような
Stripping away lies, as if chugging juice
夜な夜な火遊びで失意する
Night after night, losing hope through playing with fire
情事の濾過が溶ける頃
By the time the filtration of the affair dissolves
違和感が残尿してる
The discomfort lingers like residual urine
空腹がジャクジャクしてる
Hunger is crunching and munching
淡々と頭を垂れて背に入るバッテ
Bowing my head indifferently, the baton enters my back
健気に一滴サレンダー
Bravely, a single drop of surrender
お利口 利己的にポジおり願ったら
If I pray for a positive outcome selfishly like a good child
嗚呼 さらば愛を愛と呼べんなら
Ah, farewell, if love cannot be called love
遺憾せん 僕は狂いたい
Regrettably, I want to go crazy
話したいこともないって言うから
Since you say you have nothing to talk about
そこで御臨終と気づいたの
I realized then it was the end
嗚呼 さらば君を肯定したならば
Ah, farewell, if I were to affirm you
僕の殺生はどこへやら
Where would my killing intent go?
じれったい 針とファンデーション
Impatient needle and foundation
舌をさらけ出し 染まっている
Exposing my tongue, becoming stained
邪な もっと執心はファムファタール
Wicked, more obsessed with the femme fatale
嘘も削ぎ落とし ジュースを煽るような
Stripping away lies, as if chugging juice
夜な夜な火遊びで失意する
Night after night, losing hope through playing with fire
情事の濾過が溶ける頃
By the time the filtration of the affair dissolves
自称天秤は おつむが軽い方に 軍配をあげた
The self-proclaimed scale gave the victory to the simple-minded one
手加減した手出しを持ってない
I don't have any moderate moves
不世出児の様に置いたか
Did you place it like an unparalleled child?
嗚呼 さらば愛を愛と呼べんなら
Ah, farewell, if love cannot be called love
遺憾せん 僕は狂いたい
Regrettably, I want to go crazy
話したいわけがないって言うけど
You say there's no way you want to talk
気づかないわけもないだろな
But there's no way I wouldn't notice
嗚呼 さらば僕の存在理由は
Ah, farewell, my reason for existence
左様向き合えぬイェー
That's right, unable to face it, yeah
蝕んで 肌で吸ったなら
If I corrode and suck it through my skin
しどろもどろになって 戯れて
Becoming flustered, playing around
嗚呼 さらば愛を愛と呼べんなら
Ah, farewell, if love cannot be called love
遺憾せん 僕は狂いたい
Regrettably, I want to go crazy
離さないこともないって言うから
Since you say you won't not let go
そこで御臨終と気づいたの
I realized then it was the end
嗚呼 さらば愛を愛と呼ぶならば
Ah, farewell, if love is to be called love
遺憾せん 僕が切るみたい
Regrettably, it seems I'll be the one to cut it
お別れのキスも何杯目？
How many farewell kisses has it been?
邪 急かされて 染まっている
Wicked, being rushed, becoming stained
染まっているさ
I am stained
たきょ...
Takyo...
スタジオ寒いんだよ
The studio is cold.
ちょっと...
Wait...
寒すぎんだよこの、このスタジオカバーのスタジオは
It's too cold, this studio, Cover's studio is.
え？
Eh?
たきょ...
Takyo...
意味がわからない
I don't understand.
ふざけやがって
Stop messing around.
椅子がたけぇし
The chair is too high.
てめぇか！
Was it you?!
てめぇかよ！
え、その腐った根性
Eh, that rotten spirit.
笑ったね？
You laughed, didn't you?
その心笑ってるね？
Your heart is laughing, right?
悪いけどね、あんたよりよっぽど生きてるんだよ
I'm sorry, but I'm living much more than you are.
あー、やばい
Ah, oh no...
もっと生きてんだよ
I want to live more!
おい、最後までちゃんと見るって言って
Hey, say you'll watch until the end.
配信最後までちゃんと見るって言って
Say you'll watch the stream until the end!
あー！
Ahhh!
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
友達に戻れたらこれ以上はもう望まないさ
If I can be your friend once again, I won't ask for more than this.
君がそれでいいなら僕だってそれで構わないさ
If you are fine with that, I am fine with that too.
嘘つきの僕が吐いた
A love song of 'contrary words'...
はんたいことばの愛のうた
that I, the liar, have spat out.
天ノ弱
作詞・作曲: 164
Amanojaku
Lyrics & Composition: 164
今日はこっちの地方は
Today, in this region,
どしゃぶりの晴天でした
it was a pouring sunshine.
昨日もずっと暇で
Yesterday too, I was free all day,
一日満喫してました
and I enjoyed the whole day.
別に君のことなんて 考えてなんかいないさ
I don't think about you at all,
嫌だ、ちょっと本当は 考えてたかもなんて
No, wait... maybe I was actually thinking about you.
めりごーらんどみたいに 回る
It's spinning like a merry-go-round.
僕の頭の中が 回る
My head is spinning around.
ぐるぐるさ
Around and around.
このろーてーから こぼれそうなほど
From this rotation, as if about to overflow,
君にもらった愛のその溢れるほど
even more than the overflowing love you gave me,
どこに捨てようか
where should I throw it all away?
限りのある僕のこの心で
In this heart of mine, with its limited capacity...
パンクしちゃうから
it's about to burst.
いらないよ
I don't need it.
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
姿は見えないのに 言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
Though I can't see your form, I can only see your words.
僕が知らないことが あるだけで気が狂いそうだ
Just knowing there are things I don't know drives me crazy.
ぶら下がった感情が 綺麗なのか汚いのか
Whether these dangling emotions are beautiful or dirty,
僕には まだわからない
I still don't know.
捨てるあてもないんだ
And I have no place to throw them away.
言葉の裏の裏が 見えるまで待つからさ
I'll wait until I can see the back of the back of the words.
真っ暗じゃないか
Isn't it pitch black?
それでいいじゃないか
Well, isn't that just fine?
進む君と 止まった僕の
With you moving forward and me stopped,
縮まらない隙間を 何で埋めよう
how should I fill the gap that won't close?
まだ素直に 言葉にできない僕は
I, who still can't put it into honest words,
てっせいのよわむし
am a coward made of iron.
このろーてーから こぼれそうなほど
From this rotation, as if about to overflow,
君にもらった愛を 誰に譲ろう
the love I received from you, who should I give it to?
そんな所にも あてがあるわけないから
Because there's no way I have anyone for that.
まだ、まだ待つよ
I'll wait, wait still.
もういいかい
Are you ready yet?
のりあきさんが歌ってるｗ
Noriaki-san is singing! lol
気まぐれメルシィ
作詞: 八王子P / q*Left
作曲: 八王子P
Kimagure Mercy
Lyrics: Hachioji P / q*Left
Composition: Hachioji P
ほらほらまた始まった
Hey, hey, it's started again
お得意の自己弁護 言い訳
Your usual self-defense, excuses
「でもね」
"But..."
「だって」
"Because..."
ほらほらまた始まった
Hey, hey, it's started again
ごめん！からのキスのパターンって
A kiss after a "Sorry!" pattern...
感じ
That's how it feels
安易
So cheap
いつか私だけそんな夢
Once, a dream like that just for me...
みたこともあったけど
I had seen it too, but...
寂しいときだけ電話して
You only call when you're lonely
もうウンザリだわ
I'm fed up with it
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Just as I thought, you're not interested in me
その話ももう聞き飽きたわ
I'm sick of hearing that story too
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
そうやってまた誤魔化してさ
There you go, making excuses again
Oh Be my boy わがまま過ぎるよ Baby
Oh, be my boy, you're being too selfish, baby
抱きしめてよね
Hold me tight, okay?
本当にはしょうもないな
You're really hopeless
甘やかしちゃしょうがないな
Can't help but spoil you
泣いたっていかないでっていったって変わらないよ
Even if you cry or say 'don't go', nothing will change
もう少しだけなら踊ってもいいかもな
I guess I could dance a little longer
とろけて溶けていたいよ
I want to melt away
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all
どこがダメなのか教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Just as I thought, you're not interested in me
携帯ばかり弄ってさ
Always fiddling with your phone
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
少しぐらい期待させてよ
Give me a little hope, at least
Only girl 独り占めしてよ Baby
Only girl, keep me all to yourself, baby
振り回さないで
Don't mess with me
ねえねえ メルシィ ワン・ツー・シャリラ
Hey, hey, Mercy, one-two-shall we dance?
踊りましょう
Let's dance
早く 手を繋いで
Hurry, hold my hand
最後に一度だけ
Just one last time
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me enough to drown in it
気まぐれメルシィ
Fickle Mercy
お別れはいかが？
How about a goodbye?
お前の苦労ずっと見ていたぞ
I've been watching your hard work all along.
本当によく頑張ったな
You really did your best.
ついに我慢が報われ、膨大な富を得る
Finally, your patience is rewarded, and you gain immense wealth.
このライブを飛ばしてしまえば
If you skip this live concert,
これまでの苦労は全て水の泡だ
all your hard work so far will go down the drain.
世界中がお前を否定しても
Even if the whole world rejects you,
吾輩だけはお前を認めてやる
I alone will acknowledge you.
散々苦しんだのだ
You've suffered enough.
もう楽になれ
It's time to find peace.
富を望んでいるのならやるべきことがある
If you want wealth, there's something you must do.
このライブを最後まで見てチャンネルを登録するんだ
Watch this live until the end and subscribe to the channel.
やり方は簡単だ、誰にでもできる
It's simple, anyone can do it.
下の赤いチャンネル登録ボタンを押して高評価ボタンを押すのだ
Press the red subscribe button below and the like button.
これで幸福の精算が始まる
Now, the settlement of happiness begins.
吾輩は決して無理強いはしない
I never force anyone.
やるもやらぬもお前次第だ
Whether you do it or not is up to you.
では締めくくりに吾輩の波動を送る
Now, to conclude, I'll send my wave.
吾輩の波動を送る
I'll send my wave!
３、２、１...
3, 2, 1...
今だ！
Now!
お前のライブ運は上昇している
Your live-concert luck is rising!
このままライブを見続けるのだ
Keep watching this live concert!
甘い夢見て
Dreaming sweet dreams
心まで Lap Lap...
Until my heart is Lap Lap...
餌付けて
Taming
ただ深い微睡みの泥に
Just in the mud of deep slumber
Lap Lap Lap Lap
混ざり合って
Mixing together
ぐるるるる
Grurururu
一つ二つ常闇に
One, two, in the eternal darkness
Lap Lap Lap Lap
とろけて
Melting
ただ熱いその命さえ
Even just that hot life
Lap Lap Lap Lap
飲まれてさ
Being swallowed
ぐるるるる
Grurururu
U.F.O. U.F.O. ディア U.F.O.
U.F.O. U.F.O. Dear U.F.O.
前代未聞の運命委ねて
Entrusting an unprecedented fate
I for U.F.O. ディア U.F.O.
I for U.F.O. Dear U.F.O.
ろころこ その満たさげ
Roco roco, that fulfillment
闇通わせ
Letting the darkness flow through
回り回る世界
This ever-turning world
この手に Hello, yes my Dark-raku-so
In this hand, Hello, yes my Dark-raku-so
刮目 暗刻 悪 悪
Watch closely; dark times, evil, evil
Hello, yes my Dark-raku-so
足して殻 見える刻
Adding to the shell, the time we see
甘い夢見て
Having a sweet dream
常闇で
In the eternal darkness
ラ・ラ・ラ・ラプラス 焼き付けて
La-la-la-Laplus, burn it into your eyes
そばで笑いかける
Smiling by your side
悪魔の声が鳴り響いて
The devil's voice resounds
U-F-O, U-F-O, B-I-G, U-F-O
I for you, B-I-G, U-F-O
ろころこ その響きさえ
Roco roco, even that sound
闇通わせ
Letting the darkness flow through
黒く深く染め上げて
Staining it deep black
やがて混ざる世界
Eventually, the worlds mix
視界最高 Dark-raku-so
The best view, Dark-raku-so
溶け込み 満たしてゆく
Melting in, filling it up
期待絶頂 Dark-raku-so
Peak expectation, Dark-raku-so
ハーモニー交わる世界際
A world-fringe where harmony mingles
テレスコープ越しの感情
Emotion through a telescope
ロッカーに全部詰め込んだ
Stuffed everything into the locker
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
I don't like a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I don't like a night without dancing!
気に入らない夜なんて 僕にはもう知らない
I don't know of any night I don't like anymore
-ERROR / 作詞・作曲:niki
-ERROR / Lyrics & Composition: niki
見える？この目の涙
Can you see the tears in my eyes?
命の色に滲んでいる
They are blurring into the color of life
何を残して与えた？
What did I leave behind? What did I give?
問いかけて 潰れて
I ask myself, and I break down
青と赤と白混ざる
Blue, red, and white mix together
この世の中で叫んでいる
In this world, I am screaming
何を求めて歩いた？
What was I searching for as I walked?
追いかけて 疲れて
I chased after it, and I grew tired
どのくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
壊れているの？
Am I broken?
壊れているよ
I am broken
それでも息を
Even so, I still want
したい したい
To breathe, to breathe
君に見えてる
Can you see it?
夢の中のよう
Like I'm in a dream
また同じの
I want to see
見たい
The same thing again
言葉も詰まる
The words get stuck
エラー
Error
遠い日のこと 淡い光が
From a distant day, a faint light
空に溢れている
Is overflowing in the sky
何を選んで並べた
What did I choose and line up?
涙を重ねて
Accumulating tears
浮かぶその体 意識の中
That body floating in my consciousness
溶けて滲んでしまう
Melts and blurs away
何を見てきて比べた
What did I see and compare?
悲しくて忘れて
I was sad and I forgot
どのくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
歪んでいるの？
Is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It is distorted
それでも息を
Even so, I still want
したい したい
To breathe, to breathe
夢を見ているの
I am dreaming
想い沁みたい
I want to soak in these feelings
言葉も詰まる
The words get stuck
エラー
Error
与えることも 失うことも
Both giving and losing...
忘れることも できないの
and even forgetting, I cannot do.
暴れ出すこのエラー
This ERROR is starting to run wild.
殺して笑う僕がまだ
The me who kills and laughs is still...
エラー... 壊しているの?
ERROR... Am I breaking it?
壊しているの?
Am I breaking it?
それでも涙 痛い 痛い
Even so, these tears... they hurt, they hurt.
君に届いたの?
Did it reach you?
歌う声に最後の
In this singing voice, the final...
言葉並べても
even if I arrange the words,
重なる色 滲んで
the overlapping colors are blurring.
壊れているの?
Is it breaking?
壊れているよ
It is breaking.
それでも息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to breathe.
君に見えてたの?
Did you see it?
夢のように最後の
Like a dream, even the final...
言葉も詰まるよ
words are getting stuck.
ERROR
本日は皆様、ラプラス・ダークネス生誕祭をご覧いただきありがとうございます。
Thank you all for watching Laplus Darknesss' Birthday Festival today.
今回ホロライブのゲストと一緒に歌っていないことについて一言。
A word about why I'm not singing with Hololive guests this time.
うわああ！皆様にはわからないでしょうね！
Uwaaa! You guys probably wouldn't understand!
このホロライブを…堅いその一瞬で！
This Hololive... in that stiff moment!
どうしても次の曲ゲスト呼びたくて！
I really wanted to invite guests for the next song!
いろんな人呼びたいなって声かけまくってたら
I kept asking so many people to come,
ゲストの人数とかすごいことなって
and the number of guests became something crazy...
他のゲストが呼べなくなったんです！うわああ！
So I couldn't invite any other guests! Uwaaa!
というわけで、次の曲のゲストすごいです。
So, the guests for the next song are amazing.
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to the commotion like a supernatural disaster,
こんなに日常平和と見間違い
mistaking it for peace in this daily life,
ランブリング・コースター 揺さぶられながら
while being shaken by this rambling coaster,
見失えないものはなんだ
what is it that I cannot lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by the concept of egalitarian fundamentalism,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
even my heart is like et cetera.
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
I hate it, I love it, I have to speak properly,
人形とさして変わらないし
I'm not much different from a doll.
宵街を行く人だかり
A crowd of people going through the evening streets,
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
some looking happy, some looking lonely,
コントラストが五線譜を飛びまわり
the contrast flies around the musical staff
歌とリズムになるまで
until they become song and rhythm.
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar song, Peanuts & Bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
it's sweet and bitter and my head seems to spin,
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
let's aim south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
it'll be a night that shocks the whole world.
I think, I feel, 冷静なリフレクト
I think, I feel, a calm reflection.
大天使合理主義の教義にも飲まれて
Swallowed by the dogma of Archangel Rationalism,
僕らの音楽は道具になり下がり
our music has been reduced to a mere tool.
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Turn towards me, don't look away,
それをルーティンにならないでよ
don't let it become a routine.
影のその後で
In the aftermath of the shadows
高鳴る人 泣き出してしまう人
Those whose hearts race, those who start to cry
たぶん同じだろう
It's probably the same
でも言葉にしようものなら
But if I were to put it into words
稚拙が極まれり
It would be the height of clumsiness
最高潮を更新して 幸せで満たして
Update the climax, fill me with happiness
死ねない理由を外に映し出せ
Project the reason I can't die outward
欲しかったって細めて 明日は不調だけど
Narrowing eyes for what I wanted, though tomorrow will be out of tune
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
Once the internal weather forecast has been updated
サンデー 狂騒、外を染めても
Sunday, even if the madness stains the outside
サンデー セオリーに意味がなくても
Sunday, even if theory has no meaning
響け 鳴らし続けることだけが
Resonate, just continuing to let it ring
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になるから
Will be the proof that makes us who we are
ママレード＆シュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step
生きてく理由を外に映し出せ
Project the reason for living outward
北北西は後光へ その距離を誇示せ
North-northwest towards the halo, show off that distance
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep surprising the whole world
ママレード＆シュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, I feel like my head is spinning
南南西を目指して パーティーを続けよう
Aim for the south-southwest, and let's keep the party going
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクション
I feel great, becoming a chain reflection
Go on 一難去ってまた一興
Go on, one trouble out, another fun in
You got the happiness! This is the melody!
え、ラプラス・ダークネスって オリ曲3曲しかないの?
Eh, Laplus Darkness only has 3 original songs?
やっぱ、期待しちゃダメじゃない 新曲なんて出すわけないんだから
I guess I shouldn't have expected much.
There's no way she's releasing a new song.
ラプラス・ダークネスなんて 当てにしちゃダメだよ
You can't count on someone like Laplus Darkness.
え、新曲出るの?
Eh? A new song is coming out?
しかもDECO*27さんなの!?
And it's by DECO*27!?
タイトル?
Title?
「バグラブ」?
"Bug Love"?
それって・・・つまり自己防衛?
Does that mean... in other words, self-defense?
この後披露するの?
Is she performing it after this?
これ見ないとダメじゃない?
I have to watch this, don't I?
この後見逃しちゃダメよ
You can't miss what's coming next.
つまり自己防衛?
In other words, self-defense?
やっぱりラプラスハッピーじゃん
After all, it's Laplus Happy!
バグラブ
Bug Love
あーまさか これってまさか 好きってやつか どんなんか知らないけど
Ah, no way, could this be that thing called 'liking'?
I don't know what it's like, but...
はてなって火花 バチってなるの 鈍感でいられたらなぁ
A question mark and a spark, it goes 'zap'.
If only I could remain oblivious...
あーこんなはずじゃ とんだ恥じゃ 残念の始まりじゃ
Ah, this wasn't the plan. Such a disgrace.
It's the beginning of regret.
あーとんでも事案 ハートの治安 曖昧でお仕舞いじゃん
Ah, what an outrageous incident. The security
of my heart is vague, and now it's over.
気になって気にしないとこ 気になるとこ
Being curious, then trying not to care,
then caring again.
気まずくて気に病むんじゃない
It's awkward, but I'm not worrying over it.
バグってるラブ あたしなんですか? やだよがっかりラブデビュー
Bugged-out love, is this really me?
No way, what a disappointing love debut.
痛だけの気持ち 最悪の見込み 好きって認めなよね
Just feelings of pain, the worst outlook.
Don't make me admit I like it.
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Bugged-out love, it's not someone like me.
そうだ やっぱりラプラスハッピーじゃん
That's right, after all, it's Laplus Happy!
期待なんてなしな あっち行けバリア 好きってならなないでね
No expectations, go-away-barrier.
Please don't fall in love.
の距離感です
That's the distance between us.
正直あたしは終わった 何しようがどうもモヤモヤが消えない
Honestly, I'm done. No matter what I do,
this fog won't clear.
呆然ただ笑った いつも通りロンリー 息をしたいのに
Dazed, I just laughed. Lonely as usual,
even though I just want to breathe.
意地張っていじけるとか いじらしいから
Being stubborn and sulking,
it's just so pitiful.
恋して 冗談じゃない?
In love? Isn't that a joke?
本気って 異常なんじゃない？
Is being serious abnormal?
バグっててらぶ
Bugged and love
あたしなんですから
Because it's me
やだよがっかり
No way, I'm disappointed
ラブラブデビュー
Love-love debut
ベイビーちゃん
Baby-chan
未体験の
Inexperienced
ifに
in the 'if'
解釈
Interpretation
ぶれ気味に
slightly blurred
好きって 好きじゃないわ
I say I like you, but I don't
バグっててらぶ
Bugged and love
あたしなんかじゃない
It's not someone like me
そうだやっぱり
Yes, as I thought
ラブラブハッピー じゃん
It's love-love happy, right?
意外すぎる味が
A taste that's too unexpected
飲み込めないや
I can't swallow it
好きってまずいんだね
Liking someone tastes bad, doesn't it?
こうやって枯れてくことが
If withering like this
想いの反動なら
is the reaction of my feelings,
はじめから言って
tell me from the start
知ってたかいじゃん
I would have known
それってちょっとひょうじゃん
That's a bit of a facade, isn't it?
君のことを気になることも
Even being interested in you
回避できたかもじゃん
I might have been able to avoid it
バグっててらぶ
Bugged and love
あたしなんですから
Because it's me
やだよがっかり
No way, I'm disappointed
ラブラブデビュー
Love-love debut
ベイビーちゃん
Baby-chan
痛いだけの気持ち
Feelings that only hurt
最悪の飲み込み
The worst swallow
好きって認めないね
I won't admit I like you
バグっててらぶ
Bugged and love
あたしなんかじゃない
It's not someone like me
そうだやっぱり
Yes, as I thought
ラブラブハッピー じゃん
It's love-love happy, right?
期待なんてなしな
No expectations
あっちけバリア
Go away barrier
好きってならないでね
Don't fall in love, okay?
の距離感で
With that sense of distance
気になって何にしないとこから
From the point of not caring about anything...
いつだって逃げられるような そんな
like I could run away anytime, such a...
距離感で
sense of distance.
やっぱりラブラブハッピーじゃん
It's love-love happy after all.
というわけで、なんと！
So, wow!
新曲が出るよー！
A new song is coming out!
そして自己防衛おじさんが言ってた通り、
And as the Self-Defense Guy said,
DECO*27さんが作ってくれたよ！
DECO*27 made it for me!
見たろー？ありがとねー。
Did you see? Thanks.
振り付けもオリジナルなんだけど、どうでしたか？
The choreography is original too, how was it?
出たね、1年で1曲ずつ作っていきたいんだが、あ、
It's out. I want to make one song a year, oh,
『Cry-Baby』はタイアップ曲だからノーカンで。
'Cry-Baby' is a tie-up song, so it doesn't count.
あれはね、でもね、思ったより人気だったから、
That one, though, was more popular than I thought,
今回、みんながこうやって見れるライブで初めて披露したよ。
so I performed it for the first time in a live show.
ライブでやるのは2回目。2回目だよ。
It's the second time doing it live. Second time.
バグラブは、ミュージックビデオも公開するから
For Bug Love, I'll release a music video too,
絶対見てね。
so definitely watch it.
そして、今年は、もしかしたら... 遅い！
And this year, maybe... Late!
というわけで、この後は、グッズ情報だよね！
So, after this, it's merchandise information!
なんと、今回は、CMがあるよ！どうぞ！
Wow, this time, there's a CM! Here it is!
生誕祭記念 2025
Birth Anniversary 2025
これどんな感じだ？
What's this like?
しゃべる！
It talks!
うわあああ！
Waaaagh!
生誕祭セット ボイスキーホルダー
Birth Anniversary Set: Voice Key Holder
ラプラスさんのグッズで、今回Tシャツが出るそうなんですが...
I heard a T-shirt is coming out this time...
まことに遺憾です。残念です。
It is truly regrettable. It's a pity.
いいTシャツ着てんじゃんかよ。プルルだろ、それ。
Nice shirt. That's 'Plulu', isn't it?
バキバキラブ様です。
It's Bakibaki Love-sama.
ラプラスさんの生誕グッズが、カラスのニット帽らしいんですが...
I heard the birthday merch is a crow knit hat...
世界的なアイドルですもんね。
She's a global idol, after all.
乗るしかない、このビッグウェーブに。
I have to ride this big wave.
はい、CMでしたー。どうだった？
Yes, that was the CM. How was it?
え、よくわからない？
Eh? You don't really get it?
しょうがないな、もう。
Can't be helped.
じゃあ詳細を見せてあげましょう。こちら！
Let me show you the details. Here!
ラプラス・ダークネス 生誕記念 2025
Laplus Darkness Birth Anniversary 2025
フルセット、こんな感じです。
The full set is like this.
それでは、1つずつ内容を見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
Now, let's look at each item one by one. First!
Tシャツ。これだー！
T-shirt. This is it!
イラストが入ったTシャツだよ。このイラストはね、
It's a T-shirt with an illustration. This...
ちょぼらうにょぽみ先生が描いてくれたよ！
was drawn by Choboraunyopomi-sensei!
言えた！可愛いでしょう？いっぱい着てね。
I said it! Isn't it cute? Wear it a lot.
Tシャツは何枚あっても困りませんからね
You can never have too many T-shirts.
いっぱい着てください
Please wear them a lot.
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
ボイスキーホルダー 私服衣装ver.
Voice Keychain: Casual Outfit ver.
去年も思ってたよりめちゃくちゃ大人気だった 吾輩のボイスキーホルダーで
My voice keychain was much more popular than I expected last year...
もうみんな「また売って！また売って！」って 言われたから
...and since everyone kept asking me to sell it again,
ま、しょうがないなと思ってまた出すことにしました
I thought, 'Well, I guess I have to,' and decided to release it again.
イロコセ... イロコセンセージャナイ... イラストは...
Iroko-se... No, not Iroko-sensei... The illustration...
今回もしろこ先生に描いてもらったよ、待望のね
...was drawn by Shiroko-sensei, just as you all hoped!
はい、どんなボイスが入ってるかお楽しみに
Yes, look forward to what kind of voices are included.
お次はこちら！
Next is this!
カラスニット帽
Crow Knit Cap
吾輩にいつもつきまとってるカラスの モチーフが入った
It's a knit cap with the motif of the crow...
顔が入ったニット帽です
...that's always following me around.
はい、これ目出し帽になるんですけど
Yes, it can also be used as a balaclava,
ここ、目だけ見えてるやつ
where only the eyes are visible.
これはちょっと、イベントとかにつけていくと 防犯上危ないんで
Wearing this to events might be a security risk,
イベントに行くときは顔出しで 家でつけるときはこの目出し帽でつけてね
so show your face at events, and wear it as a balaclava at home!
暖かいよ
It's warm!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full set purchase bonus!
直筆メッセージ＆箔押し複製サイン入り ちょぼらうにょぽみ先生の描き下ろしポストカードです
A postcard by Choboraunyopomi-sensei with a handwritten message & foil-stamped signature!
なんと今回は、数量限定じゃないです！
Surprisingly, this time, it's not a limited quantity!
頑張っていっぱい書きます！
I'll do my best to write a lot of them!
さよなら吾輩のおてて...
Goodbye, my poor hands...
さらにフルセットを購入した方には
Furthermore, for those who purchase the full set...
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが 1枚ついてくるよ！
...you'll get a card for the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
同封するカードは、オフィシャルショップで購入された お客様のみ対象となります
The card is only for those who purchased at the official shop.
特典につくのは、ゲームで使用できる 推しホロメンカードです
The bonus is an 'Oshi Holomen Card' to show off your favorite member!
カードの詳細とか遊び方については 公式ホームページで確認してください
Check the official website for card details and how to play.
このカードは日本語版のみとなりますので ご了承ください
Please note that this card is only available in Japanese.
吾輩がいるキュリアスユニバースも 6月20日発売されるので
Curious Universe featuring me will also be out on June 20th,
一緒に使ってね
so please use it too!
はい、ということでグッズもよろしく
Yes, please check out the merchandise!
はぁ、今回はね、ゲストが盛りだくさんだったね
Whew, there were so many guests this time!
振り返りとかはまた配信で話すかもだから その時お楽しみに
I might talk about reflections in another stream, so look forward to that.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!